A Guide to the Records of St. Paul's Church in Ivy, Virginia, 1848-1993
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Records of St. Paul's Church in Ivy, Virginia, 1848-1993
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11165-a
This collection consists of ca. 1390 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This material was loaned to the Library by St. Paul's Church in Ivy, Virginia, through David J. Wood, Jr. of Charlottesville, Virginia, on May 15, 1995.
Scope and Content Information
The records of St. Paul's Episcopal Church in Ivy, Virginia consist of ca. 1390 items, 1854-1993, and include minutes of vestry meetings, 1867-1993; communicant/cash book, 1859-1876; extracts of baptisms, burials, confirmations, marriages, and parochial lists from the register, 1848-1946; and, correspondence and papers of St. Paul's and Emmanuel churches, 1854-1886. There are correspondence, legal deeds and contracts, surveys and plats, and other papers, concerning the 1963 purchase of the Lewis property adjacent to St. Paul's Church. Included among the papers removed from the bound volume of minutes of the vestry, 1867-1947, is a sermon of Frederick William Neve (1855-1948), "What Shall I do with Jesus, Which is called Christ." Three oversize items pertain to Neve's ministry at St. Paul's Church in Ivy and St. John's Church in Yeovil, England.
Contents List
- Communicant/cash book 1859-1876 (Box 1)
- Communicant/cash book, papers removed from the bound volume 1854-1886 (Box 1)
- Lewis Property 1963 (Box 1)
- Minutes of Vestry Meetings 1867-1947, Bound volume (Box 1)
- Minutes of Vestry Meetings 1864-1945 (Box 1)
  Papers removed from the bound volume, 1867-1947
- Minutes of Vestry Meetings 1948-1951 (Box 1)
- Minutes of Vestry Meetings 1951-1961, Bound volume (Box 2)
- Minutes of Vestry Meetings 1962-1977, 16 folders (Box 2)
- Minutes of Vestry Meetings 1978-1993, 16 folders (Box 3)
- Certificate to Frederick W. Neve 1935, Framed (Oversize F-4)
  In appreciation of his life and ministry on his eightieth birthday from the people of St. Paul's, Ivy.
- Resolution re Frederick W. Neve 1886 Apr 15 (Oversize 10)
  From St. John's Church, Yeovil, England upon his departure
- Resolution re Frederick W. Neve on the twenty-first anniversary of his incumbency of St. Paul's Church 1909 May (Oversize 10)